Now we've added our power up to our scene.
Now as a first step to
getting the power up to
work, we'll make it
disappear when the player
hits it and then we'll
set up a boolean value
so that we can track when
the player is picked it up.
So if we go into our player controller
script, in our player controller script, we're
going to add another method
for our on-trigger-enter.
And then we're going to
create an if statement inside.
So if the other thing that we run into is a
power up, then we should do something.
So since we get the
collider of the thing
we're running into, we
can use other and we'll
compare the tag since
we applied that when we
created our power ups,
then what we're going
to do is we're going to destroy
the power up that we pick up.
So the other game object.
Now we need to know that we
actually picked up this power up.
So we're going to create another variable.
This one will be public so we can see
when it turns on and we'll call it bool.
So that way we
know if it's on or if it's
off, if it's true or if
it's false, has power
up and we'll set this to false by default.
And then in our
on-trigger-enter, when we
run into the power up,
then we can change our
has power up variable to true,
so that way we know we have it.
And then if we click
on our player, we should
see the has power up
Boolean on our script.
When we press play,
if we run into our gem,
you can see that our has
power up has turned on.
So what you're going
to do is in your player
controller script, you're
going to add a boolean
variable for has power
up and then you're going
to create another
on-trigger-enter method.
And in that method we're going to check if
we run into an object and that object's tag
is power up, then we
set our own has power
up variable to true and we
destroy the other game object.
Now it's your turn.